A Guide to the Evert B. Clark Papers, 1949-1988
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Evert B. Clark Papers 1949-1988
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1989-022
15 boxes; 15 cu. ft.
Papers of aviation, science, and space journalist Evert B. Clark, including correspondence, memoranda, research notes; and drafts and published copies of articles.
Clark, Evert B.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Evert B. Clark Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1989.
Biographical Information
Evert B. Clark was born in Gainesville, Georgia on October 15, 1926. He served in the U. S. Navy from 1944 to 1946 and graduated from the University of North Carolina in Chapel Hill in June 1947, with an A. B. in journalism and naval science and tactics. From June 1947 to October 1948 Clark worked as a reporter, state editor, and features editor for the Durham, North Carolina Morning Herald. In November 1948 he became a reporter for the Washington, D. C. Daily News, working also as assistant city editor and aviation editor for that newspaper through December 1955.
In January 1956 Clark began working at Aviation Week Magazine, serving at various times as its Washington bureau chief, space techinlogy editor (the first space editor in the magazine's history), and military editor. He joined the Washington bureau of the New York Times in September 1963 as a science correspondent, specializing in aviation and space stories. In June 1968 he joined Newsweek magazine in its Washington bureau as a science correspondent (again specializing in aviation and space). He also covered the Watergate scandal for Newsweek from its inception to its conclusion. From April 1978 until his death, Clark was a technical editor for Business Week and other magazines connected with the McGraw-Hill World News Bureau in Washington. He died on July 7, 1988.
Clark received many awards for his writing, including the National Space Club's journalism prize in 1969, in which Clark was cited for his "penetrating, consistently informed and lucid writing on all phases of the national space program: sometimes critical, always objective and thorough, resulting in outstanding reporting to the world at large." The National Press Foundation has established an award in Clark's memory. The Evert Clark Award, presented annually to a journalist 30 or younger, is intended to encourage young science writers by recognizing outstanding reporting in the science area. The award was first presented in 1990.
Scope and Content
The Evert B. Clark Papers contain many of Clark's notes, files, and much of his correspondence, for stories and research projects from throughout his career.
Arrangement
Boxes 1-9 contain subject files and correspondence, arranged by date. Boxes 10-13 contain clippings of articles Clark wrote for the Washington Daily News, Aviation Week, the New York Times, Newsweek and Business Week, as well as his drafts for articles for Newsweek. Part of Box 13 and all of Box 14 contain Clark's research files for the book Contrabandista!, which he and and Nicholas Horrock published in 1973, as well as Clark's research files for a projected book on space weapons, never published. (A third book project on the Glomar Explorer and underseas espionage, referred to as "Project Jennifer," is represented by files in the main body of the collection.) Box 15 contains oversize materials; their existence is also noted where they would have fit chronologically in the main body of the collection.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Authors; Science and Technology
Contents List
- General correspondence 1949 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Truman inauguration invitation 1949 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Simple Jim article (Washington Daily News) clipping, correspondence 1949 (Box-folder 1-3)
- General correspondence 1950-1951 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Personal correspondence 1951-1965 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Benny Pace article (Washington Daily News) 1953 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Donald M. Jacobs notes 1953-1955 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Donald M. Jacobs notebooks 1955 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Mare Island, California centennial 1954 (Box-folder 1-9-10)
- Hughes Aircraft Company photos 1955 (Box-folder 1-11)
- X-1A explosion 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Space exploration - historical 1955-1967 (Box-folder 1-13)
- General correspondence 1956 (Box-folder 1-14)
- X-2 research airplane 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Résumé and clippings from Aviation Week and Washington Daily News1955-1967 (Box-folder 1-16)
- Aeroflot 1956-1968 (Box-folder 1-17)
- General correspondence 1957 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Space exploration - historical documents 1957-1958 (Box-folder 1-19)
- Aviation Week correspondence 1957-1963 (Box-folder 1-20)
- President's Science Advisotry Committee, Office of Science and Technology 1957-1968 (Box-folder 1-21)
- Space exploration - sociological aspects 1957-1972 (Box-folder 1-22)
- General correspondence 1958 (Box-folder 1-23)
- Aviation Week correspondence 1958 (Box-folder 1-24)
- Life magazine cover with Evert B. Clark in background 1958, [see Oversize Materials, Box 15]
- X-15 program 1958 (Box-folder 1-25)
- Space exploration - general reference materials 1958-1965 (Box-folder 1-26)
- General correspondence 1959 (Box-folder 1-27)
- "High Altitude Cloud Photography" 1959 (Box-folder 1-28)
- Space exploration 1959 (Box-folder 1-29)
- International Aeronatucial Federation 1959 (Box-folder 1-30)
- Space exploration - quotations and miscellany 1959-1966 (Box-folder 1-31)
- Charles U. Daly ca.1959-1966 (Box-folder 1-32)
- General correspondence 1960 (Box-folder 1-33)
- First non-stop flight U. S. A. F. tactical jets (Aviation Week) ca.1960 (Box-folder 1-34)
- Supersonic air transports 1960 (Box-folder 1-35)
- Lasers 1960-1977 (Box-folder 1-36-37)
- General correspondence 1961 (Box-folder 1-38)
- Soviet space program 1961 (Box-folder 1-39)
- Space rescue 1961-1966 (Box-folder 1-40)
- Space exploration - policy and history 1962-1967 (Box-folder 2-1)
- U-2 1962-1969 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Venus 1962-1969 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Nuclear energy 1962-1970 (Box-folder 2-4)
- General correspondence 1963 (Box-folder 2-5)
- Saturday Evening Post correspondence 1963 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Correspondence concerning move to New York Times1963 (Box-folder 2-7)
- "What Is It In Space-Age Russian" by M. S. Vartanoff 1963 (Box-folder 2-8)
- General reference materials 1963 (Box-folder 2-9)
- Supersonic transport 1963 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Soviet supersonic transport 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Aviation Week correspondence 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2-12)
- Gemini/Titan 9, Vostoks 5 and 6 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2-13)
- Expense accounts 1963-1965 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Miscellaneous photographs and clippings 1963-1983 (Box-folder 2-15)
- General correspondence 1964 (Box-folder 2-16)
- New York Times correspondence 1964 (Box-folder 2-17)
- "Nuclear Propulsion for Rockets" 1964 (Box-folder 2-18)
- Mafia 1964 (Box-folder 2-19)
- Strategy 1964-1968 (Box-folder 2-20)
- Space exploration - history / Apollo background 1964-1969 (Box-folder 2-21)
- New York Times annual reports, miscellaneous 1964-1975 (Box-folder 2-22)
- General correspondence 1965 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Gemini-Titan 3 1965 (Box-folder 2-24)
- Gemini-Titan 4 1965 (Box-folder 2-25)
- Gemini-Titan 5 1965 (Box-folder 2-26-27)
- Gemini-Titan 6 1965 (Box-folder 2-28)
- U. S. Air Force astronaut maneuvering unit handbook ca.1965 (Box-folder 2-29)
- Satellites 1965 (Box-folder 2-30)
- Henry Coanda 1965 (Box-folder 2-31)
- Soviet aviation 1965 (Box-folder 2-32)
- OSCAR (Orbital Satellite Carrying Amateur Radio) correspondence 1965 (Box-folder 2-33)
- Basic Foundation Inc. claim statement 1965 (Box-folder 2-34)
- Space exploration - history 1965 (Box-folder 2-35)
- Miscellaneous memoranda 1965 (Box-folder 2-36)
- Robert Goddard 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Space exploration articles and speeches 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Supersonic transport - correspondence 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3-3)
- "New Horizons" scripts 1965-1967 (Box-folder 3-4)
- President's Science Advisotry Council (PSAC) 1965-1968 (Box-folder 3-5)
- Space exploration - international issues 1965-1968 (Box-folder 3-6)
- New York Times Washington Bureau correspondence 1965-1968 (Box-folder 3-7)
- Earth resources 1965-1969 (Box-folder 3-8)
- Photographs 1965-1969 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Astronautics & Aeronatics correspondence 1965-1970 (Box-folder 3-10)
- Space exploration - miscellaneous 1965-1971 (Box-folder 3-11-12)
- Compton's Encyclopedia correspondence 1965-1972 (Box-folder 3-13)
- General correspondence 1966 (Box-folder 3-14)
- Spacecraft rockets and systems ca.1966 (Box-folder 3-15)
- Surveyor I 1966 (Box-folder 3-16)
- "Around the World in 800 Minutes" (Finance Magazine) 1966 (Box-folder 3-17)
- Nuclear weapons development ca.1966 (Box-folder 3-18)
- "Space Rescue" by E. Konecci 1966 (Box-folder 3-19)
- Surveyor I 1966 (Box-folder 3-20)
- Gemini 12 press reference 1966 (Box-folder 3-21)
- Expense accounts 1966 (Box-folder 3-22)
- "The Scientific-Government-Industrial Machine" (New Republic) 1966 (Box-folder 3-23)
- Coal study - clippings, etc. 1966 (Box-folder 3-24)
- Aircraft noise reduction - correspondence 1966 (Box-folder 3-25)
- Eastern Airlines (New York Times article) correspondence 1966 (Box-folder 3-26)
- Unidentified flying objects 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3-27)
- Miscellaneous stories 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3-28)
- True Magazine article on Surveyor I 1966 (Box-folder 3-29)
- Aviation Week correspondence 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3-30)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science writing awards - correspondence 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3-31)
- Soviet Union space program 1966-1968 (Box-folder 3-32)
- Earth-Moon 1966-1970 (Box-folder 3-33)
- Personal correspondence 1966-1973 (Box-folder 3-34)
- Glomar Explorer 1966-1975 (Box-folder 3-35)
- General correspondence 1967 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Satellites 1967 (Box-folder 4-2)
- Apollo - historical perspectives 1967 (Box-folder 4-3)
- Otto K. Krausskopf (Flugwelt International) - correspondence 1967 (Box-folder 4-4)
- Manned Orbiting Laboratory 1967 (Box-folder 4-5)
- Gemini Agena Target press handbook 1967 (Box-folder 4-6)
- Computers 1967 (Box-folder 4-7)
- Gemini / Titan II Launch Vehicle press handbook 1967 (Box-folder 4-8)
- Apollo - "Meet the Press" May 21 1967 (Box-folder 4-9)
- Apollo fire Jan 27 1967 (Box-folder 4-10)
- Apollo Guidance and Navigation News Reference 1967 (Box-folder 4-11)
- Wright Memorial Dinner 1967 (Box-folder 4-12)
- James Webb 1967 (Box-folder 4-13)
- Names 1967 (Box-folder 4-14)
- Collier's Year Book missile article 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4-15)
- Newspeak, airline tickets 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4-16)
- Soviet Union space program 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4-17)
- Aeroflot 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4-18)
- Planets - general n.d. (Box-folder 4-19)
- Mars 1967-1969 (Box-folder 4-20)
- Apollo 1967-1969 (Box-folder 4-21)
- Asteroids 1967-1970 (Box-folder 4-22)
- Meteorites 1967-1970 (Box-folder 4-23)
- Solar system 1967-1970 (Box-folder 4-24)
- Saturday Review correspondence 1967-1972 (Box-folder 4-25)
- General correspondence 1968 (Box-folder 4-26-27)
- Trip to Moscow 1968 (Box-folder 4-28)
- Orbiting Astronautical Observatory 1968 (Box-folder 4-29)
- Aviation Writers Association writing award 1968 (Box-folder 4-30)
- Space exploration - historical 1968 (Box-folder 4-31)
- Pluto 1968 (Box-folder 4-32)
- Marine resources - correspondence 1968 (Box-folder 4-33)
- Apollo 8 and 9 1968 (Box-folder 4-34)
- Technology alphabets and languages - clippings 1968 (Box-folder 4-35)
- Aeroflot notebooks 1968 (Box-folder 4-36)
- Apollo 7 "Meet the Press" Nov 10 1968 (Box-folder 4-37)
- Vanguard I memorabilia 1968 (Box-folder 4-38)
- Saturn 5 News Reference 1968 (Box-folder 4-39)
- Saturn IB News Reference 1968 (Box-folder 4-40)
- Apollo 8 - Time clippings 1968 (Box-folder 4-41)
- Apollo 8 lunar orbit chart 1968 (Box-folder 4-42)
- "Man Reaches for the Moon" trial chapter for National Geographic book 1968 (Box-folder 4-43)
- Enclyclopedia Brittanica Yearkbook article, "Astronautics: Satellite and Space Probes" 1968 (Box-folder 4-44)
- Nuclear bomb capability of France and China 1968 (Box-folder 4-45)
- Apollo 8 reaction 1968-1969 (Box-folder 5-1)
- Military-industrial complex 1968-1969 (Box-folder 5-2)
- Aeroflot 1968-1970 (Box-folder 5-3)
- Spy satellites 1968-1970 (Box-folder 5-4)
- Apollo memorabilia 1968-1970 (Box-folder 5-5)
- Miscellaneous notes and documents 1968-1971 (Box-folder 5-6-7)
- Science policy 1968-1971 (Box-folder 5-8)
- General correspondence 1969 (Box-folder 5-9)
- Apollo 8 correspondence 1969 (Box-folder 5-10)
- Apollo program - Newsweek clippings 1969 (Box-folder 5-11)
- Newsweek letters to the editor concerning the Jan 6 and Feb 3 issues 1969 (Box-folder 5-12)
- Apollo program - Time clippings 1969 (Box-folder 5-13)
- Apollo 11 science experiments 1969 (Box-folder 5-14)
- Apollo 11 drafts (Newsweek) 1969 (Box-folder 5-15)
- Apollo 11 post-flight conference Aug 12 1969, [cassette] (Box-folder 5-16)
- Supersonic transport 1969 (Box-folder 5-17)
- Newsweek special space report - drafts, etc. 1969 (Box-folder 5-18)
- Apollo 11 (Newsweek) Jul 28 1969 (Box-folder 5-19)
- Apollo - Life clippings 1969 (Box-folder 5-20)
- Clark - "Meet the Press" panels 1969 (Box-folder 5-21)
- Apollo 11 documents 1969 (Box-folder 5-22-23)
- Apollo 11 memorabilia 1969, [see Oversize Materials, Box 15]
- Apollo 11 media briefing 1969 (Box-folder 5-24)
- Apollo 11 flight plan 1969 (Box-folder 5-25)
- Apollo 11 - correspondence 1969 (Box-folder 5-26)
- National Space Club - press award, Goddard Memorial Dinner Mar 5 1969 (Box-folder 5-27)
- World peace 1969 (Box-folder 5-28)
- Miscellaneous freelance 1969-1970 (Box-folder 5-29)
- Apollo Executive Group 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6-1)
- Lee DuBridge 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6-2)
- Jupiter 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6-3)
- Howard Kurtz 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6-4)
- Intelligence 1969-1971 (Box-folder 6-5)
- Glomar Explorer 1969-1975 (Box-folder 6-6)
- Newsweek personal correspondence 1969-1975 (Box-folder 6-7)
- Lasers - warfare 1969-1977 (Box-folder 6-8)
- Awards 1969-1986 (Box-folder 6-9)
- General correspondence 1970 (Box-folder 6-10)
- Aviation / Space Writers' Association 1970 (Box-folder 6-11)
- "The Moon Program's Business Brain Trust" (Nation's Business) 1970 (Box-folder 6-12)
- Grumman Aerospace Corporation notebook 1970 (Box-folder 6-13)
- Apollo 12 Spacecraft News Reference ca.1970 (Box-folder 6-14)
- Book on the solar system 1970 (Box-folder 6-15)
- Milsat 1970 (Box-folder 6-16)
- Sun 1970 (Box-folder 6-17)
- Mercury 1970 (Box-folder 6-18)
- Spy satellite 1970 (Box-folder 6-19)
- Ocean mining - Prospector research vessel 1970 (Box-folder 6-20)
- Nation's Business correspondence 1970 (Box-folder 6-21)
- Science and society 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6-22)
- Apollo 15 Spacecraft News Reference 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6-23)
- War and Space by R. Salkeld 1970-1977 (Box-folder 6-24)
- General correspondence 1971 (Box-folder 6-25)
- Alexei N. Kosygin visit to Canada 1971 (Box-folder 6-26)
- Extraterrestrial life (Time) Dec 13 1971 (Box-folder 6-27)
- Intelligence - notebooks 1971, [4 items] (Box-folder 6-28)
- Intelligence 1971 (Box-folder 6-29)
- Apollo 15 certificate of award 1971 (Box-folder 6-30)
- Intelligence - science and the CIA 1971 (Box-folder 6-31)
- Intelligence - notes and drafts 1971 (Box-folder 6-32)
- Travel in China (Newsweek) 1971 (Box-folder 6-33)
- Intelligence 1971-1972 (Box-folder 7-1)
- Watergate - IRS 1971-1974, [see Oversize Materials, Box 15]
- Glomar Explorer 1971-1977 (Box-folder 7-2-3)
- Intelligence - microwave interception, telephone security 1971-1978 (Box-folder 7-4)
- General correspondence 1972 (Box-folder 7-5)
- Lasers - Bell Laboratories 1972-1976 (Box-folder 7-6)
- Summa Corporation - Howard Hughes 1972-1976 (Box-folder 7-7)
- General correspondence 1973 (Box-folder 7-8)
- "Press Conference USA" (Newsweek) ca.1973 (Box-folder 7-9)
- Apollo 17 correspondence 1973 (Box-folder 7-10)
- Watergate - clippings and notes 1973-1974 (Box-folder 7-11)
- William Spector - narcotics 1973-1975 (Box-folder 7-12)
- General correspondence 1974 (Box-folder 7-13)
- CIA - James Jesus Angleton 1974 (Box-folder 7-14)
- Notes for a book on Watergate ca.1974 (Box-folder 7-15)
- N/W newsletter 1974 (Box-folder 7-16)
- Unidentified cassette 1974 (Box-folder 7-17)
- Watergate tape transcripts 1974 (Box-folder 7-18)
- Exploration of the Solar System" (AIAA) 1974 (Box-folder 7-19)
- "Mood in the Bunkers" - Richard Nixon 1974 (Box-folder 7-20)
- John E. Bacon project - international drug trafficking 1974 (Box-folder 7-21)
- Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute 1974-1975 (Box-folder 7-22)
- Ocean resources - laws and rights 1974-1976 (Box-folder 7-23)
- Lasers 1974-1977 (Box-folder 7-24-25)
- Landsat (earth resources satellite) - documents and brochures 1974-1977 (Box-folder 7-26)
- General correspondence 1975 (Box-folder 8-1)
- N/W newsletters 1975 (Box-folder 8-2)
- Project M.I.S. - intelligence eavesdropping and surveillance 1975 (Box-folder 8-3)
- Robert Watson-Watt - radar 1975 (Box-folder 8-4)
- Notebook notes 1975 (Box-folder 8-5-6)
- Project Jennifer - Holystone 1975 (Box-folder 8-7)
- Undersea photography 1975 (Box-folder 8-8)
- Undersea - general 1975 (Box-folder 8-9)
- Summa burglary 1975 (Box-folder 8-10)
- Project Jennifer (submarines) - general 1975 (Box-folder 8-11)
- Soviet-U.S. relations 1975 (Box-folder 8-12)
- "Original Notes" 1975 (Box-folder 8-13)
- Ocean mining 1975 (Box-folder 8-14)
- Academy of Space Scribes awards 1975 (Box-folder 8-15)
- Glomar Explorer - Newsweek files 1975 (Box-folder 8-16)
- William Spector cassette 1975 (Box-folder 8-17)
- [McClintic?] cassette May 1975 (Box-folder 8-18)
- Deep Throat ca.1975 (Box-folder 8-19)
- Names ca.1975 (Box-folder 8-20)
- Drug trafficking ca.1975 (Box-folder 8-21)
- Astronautics & Aeronautics correspondence 1975 (Box-folder 8-22)
- Notes 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-23)
- Bugging and phone security 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-24)
- Project Jennifer / Glomar Explorer, Challenger, etc. 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-25)
- Project Jennifer 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-26)
- CIA and KGB 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-27)
- Seabed missiles 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-28)
- Glomar Explorer 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-29)
- Law of the sea 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-30)
- Oil 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-31)
- Ocean - general 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8-32)
- Monitor Marine Sanctuary 1975-1977 (Box-folder 8-33)
- Earthquakes 1975-1977 (Box-folder 8-34)
- Holt, Rinehart - contract for Project Jennifer 1975-1977 (Box-folder 8-35)
- Lasers 1975-1978 (Box-folder 8-36)
- Business Week space war story award 1975-1981 (Box-folder 8-37)
- General correspondence 1976 (Box-folder 8-38)
- N/W newsletter 1976 (Box-folder 8-39)
- Project Jennifer outline 1976 (Box-folder 8-40)
- Daniel K. Ludwig - Washington Post clipping 1976 (Box-folder 8-41)
- Nicaragua - I.B.M. bribe 1976 (Box-folder 8-42)
- Glomar Explorer 1976 (Box-folder 8-43)
- Viking 1976 (Box-folder 8-44)
- Seabed 1976 (Box-folder 8-45)
- Stanley Foundation 1976 (Box-folder 8-46-47)
- Science 1976 (Box-folder 8-48)
- Deepsea Ventures notebook 1976 (Box-folder 8-49)
- Lasers - space shuttle 1976 (Box-folder 8-50)
- Carl Sagan 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9-1)
- Richard Wohl 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9-2)
- Astronautics & Aeronautics 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9-3)
- Science - miscellaneous 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9-4)
- Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9-5)
- Project Jennifer 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9-6)
- Eavesdropping / intelligence 1977-1978 (Box-folder 9-7)
- War in Space indexes and files 1976-1978 (Box-folder 9-8)
- Newsweek correspondence 1976-1978 (Box-folder 9-9)
- Novel 1977 (Box-folder 9-10)
- Spacewar outline ca.1977 (Box-folder 9-11)
- Carl Sagan 1977 (Box-folder 9-12)
- Search for Extraterrestrial Intelligence (SETI) 1977 (Box-folder 9-13)
- Satellite target 1977 (Box-folder 9-14)
- Communications interception 1977 (Box-folder 9-15)
- Speech - information from the press to the CIA ca.1977 (Box-folder 9-16)
- Mulcahy notebook 1977 (Box-folder 9-17)
- Jet Propulsion Laboratory fact sheets 1977 (Box-folder 9-18)
- Science policy 1977 (Box-folder 9-19)
- Notes and drafts - Mars, Monitor, Voyager 1976-1977 (Box-folder 9-20)
- General correspondence 1977 (Box-folder 9-21)
- Telecommunications Privacy Act of 1977 1977 (Box-folder 9-22)
- Charged particle beams 1977 (Box-folder 9-23)
- Origins of life 1977 (Box-folder 9-24)
- Voyager to Jupiter 1977 (Box-folder 9-25)
- Wernher von Braun 1977 (Box-folder 9-26)
- Richard Wohl - lasers 1977-1978 (Box-folder 9-27)
- Science research and development - Dr. Frank Press 1977-1978 (Box-folder 9-28)
- General correspondence 1978 (Box-folder 9-29)
- Health care notes ca.1978 (Box-folder 9-30)
- Space - space shuttle 1978 (Box-folder 9-31)
- Eavesdropping 1978 (Box-folder 9-32)
- Heineman and Califano drafts and notes 1978 (Box-folder 9-33)
- From Newsweek to McGraw-Hill 1978 (Box-folder 9-34)
- Boeing - solar energy 1978 (Box-folder 9-35)
- Mystery booms 1978 (Box-folder 9-36)
- Derailment 1978 (Box-folder 9-37)
- Spacewar contract correspondence 1978-1979 (Box-folder 9-38)
- Keegan 1979 (Box-folder 9-39)
- Book review (The Washington Post) 1979-1980 (Box-folder 9-40)
- Space shuttle press information ca.1980 (Box-folder 9-41)
- Project Jennifer ca.1981 (Box-folder 9-42)
- Donovan book reviews 1982 (Box-folder 9-43)
- Space telescope 1982-1985 (Box-folder 9-44)
- Lockheed 1984 (Box-folder 9-45)
- Newsletters - National Association of Science Writers and the Foreign Intelligence Literary Scene 1987 (Box-folder 9-46)
- Directory of Public Information Contacts, Washington D. C. 1987 (Box-folder 9-47)
- Periscope - Association of Former Intelligence Officers 1987 (Box-folder 9-48)
- Miscellaneous 1987 (Box-folder 9-49)
- The Business of Science by S. Ramo 1988 (Box-folder 9-50)
- Phone list 1988 (Box-folder 9-51)
- Armed Services Committee - Dr. Robert Rosenzweig oral statement 1988 (Box-folder 9-52)
- Business intelligence - W. Colby, C. Balaam 1988 (Box-folder 9-53)
- General correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 9-54)
- Washington Daily News clippings 1948-1952 (Box-folder 10-1-3)
- Washington Daily News Jacobs press releases - clippings 1951-1952 (Box-folder 10-4-5)
- Washington Daily News - clippings, Bratburd, Wiretap series, Shimon case, flying saucers 1952 (Box-folder 10-6)
- Washington Daily News clippings 1953 (Box-folder 10-7)
- Washington Daily News clippings, notes 1953-1955 (Box-folder 10-8)
- Washington Daily News clippings 1954-1955 (Box-folder 10-9-10)
- Aviation Week clippings 1955-1962 (Box-folder 10-11-20)
- New York Times clippings 1963-1964 (Box-folder 10-21)
- New York Times supersonic transport clippings 1963-1965 (Box-folder 10-22)
- New York Times clippings 1963-1968 (Box-folder 10-23-24)
- New York Times space clippings (excluding Gemini) 1964-1967 (Box-folder 10-25)
- New York Times Gemini clippings 1965 (Box-folder 10-26)
- New York Times Gemini clippings 1965 (Box-folder 11-1)
- New York Times clippings (excluding Gemini and SST) 1965 (Box-folder 11-2)
- New York Times clippings 1965-1968 (Box-folder 11-3)
- New York Times clippings (excluding Gemini and SST 1966 (Box-folder 11-4)
- New York Times Surveyor clippings 1966 (Box-folder 11-5)
- New York Times clippings 1966-1968 (Box-folder 11-6)
- New York Times Soviet satellite Cosmos 146 clippings 1967 (Box-folder 11-7)
- New York Times Soviet Soyuz 1 clippings 19 (Box-folder 11-8)
- New York Times air traffic saftety clippings 1967 (Box-folder 11-9)
- New York Times clippings 1967-1968 (Box-folder 11-10-11)
- Newsweek clippings 1968-1974 (Box-folder 11-12-18)
- Newsweek Watergate clippings 1974 (Box-folder 11-19)